وَدَّ كَثِیْرٌ مِّنْ اَهْلِ الْكِتٰبِ لَوْ یَرُدُّوْنَكُمْ مِّنْۢ بَعْدِ اِیْمَانِكُمْ كُفَّارًا ۚۖ حَسَدًا مِّنْ عِنْدِ اَنْفُسِهِمْ
حَسَدًا مِّنْ عِنْدِ اَنْفُسِهِمْ مِّنْۢ بَعْدِ مَا تَبَیَّنَ لَهُمُ
مِّنْۢ بَعْدِ مَا تَبَیَّنَ لَهُمُ الْحَقُّۚ
فَاعْفُوْا وَ اصْفَحُوْا حَتّٰى یَاْتِیَ اللّٰهُ بِاَمْرِهٖؕ
اِنَّ اللّٰهَ عَلٰى كُلِّ شَیْءٍ قَدِیْرٌ۞
Allahسبحانه وتعالى says in His book, which we might be translate,
that many of the people of the Scripture desire to turn you back from your faith, revert you away from your faith,
and make you unbelievers; Kuffar(کفار) after the truth has become clear to them out of jealousy.
And Allahسبحانه وتعالى says that we should overlook and pardon, until Allah comes with another command,
and that other command was the Jihad(جہاد), the command to wage Jihad(جہاد) in the path of Allah,
as this verse was revealed before the regulations of Jihad(جہاد) were finalized.
So therefore it is in no surprise, or it should be no surprise to the Muslims
that there are unbelievers, who wish to turn us back from our faith.
However though, we live in a time which is unique, and that is because of two factors;
On the one hand, we face a time when the Islamic Ummah(امۃ) has reached its lowest point in history.
Our Ummah(امۃ) has reached the lowest point in history, and this weakness that we face is not restricted to one area as opposed to another.
There is a weakness in our faith.
There is a weakness in our understanding and our knowledge.
There is a weakness in our conduct and our moral behavior.
There is a weakness in the political sense.
There is a weakness in terms of the economic sense.
There is a weakness in the Da'wah(دعوۃ) sense.
There is a weakness in the sense of lack of unity.
The weakness that the Ummah(امۃ) faces is not restricted to one area, as opposed to another.
At the same time, we face an enemy which has reached its strongest point in its history,
and is able to influence the world as no other people have been able to influence it throughout history.
This is a reality that we must deal with.
But there's another issue, the issue of the coming of the end of the second millennium, since the birth of Eesa Ibne Maryamعلیہ السلام.
The Christians have certain beliefs, and it is from these beliefs that many of their actions must be interpreted.
And one of their main beliefs is that when Jesus returns to Earth,
a belief which we share with them, that Jesus will return, that his return comes at the beginning or end of a millennium.
And that's why, historically, around the year 1000 the Christians were waiting for Jesus to return, علیہ السلام,
and they fled from their cities, occupying the mountains and the outlying areas waiting for His coming.
And when he did not show back, they returned back and waited patiently for 1000 years.
This idea that Jesus's eminent return is at hand, is an idea which moves these Christian organizations.
And as we shall see in the lecture, that we will find a statement made by George Otis, one of the major Christian evangelical people,
who has written one of the books that we have before us,
where we'll see that he says at the end of the lecture
that we say that I believe that this generation, meaning (the people) us, this is a Christian guide saying;
barring any kind of massive disobedience, will be the generation at station, at the time of the Lord Jesus Christ return
تَعٰلٰى اللہ الذلک عُلُوًّا كَبِیْرًا
To claim; what rightfully is, meaning the earth.
So they have a political and a social and an economic and a dominance on the world.
This is a reality, plus they have a motivation.
A motivation that they are the last generation,
and so therefore, they are preparing themselves for the ultimate conclusion.
What is that ultimate conclusion, the battle of Armageddon.
And it is my great sorrow and my apology that I forgot the book in the apartment, where I am staying in,
written by one of the major Christian evangelicals, Hal Lindsey, who wrote a book in the 1970s called “The Late Great Planet Earth”,
which sold over 19 million copies, and has recently put a book called “The final battle”.
And the cover of that book shows you a nuclear mushroom cloud and if you read the contents of the book is that Jesus is on the way.
And therefore the eventual battle with the Muslims and their annihilation, which the Christian evangelicals interpret
as they're striking the Islamic world with nuclear warheads,
and then the Christians being raised above the clouds in the rapture; This is their belief.
Is I hat.
So we have resources and we have motivation,
and so therefore, for the Christians now this is their hour,
and they see that this is their final opportunity to save us,
because they feel that it's just a matter of just a few years before they will have to put the swords to our neck.
So it is from this desire to save us, as they say,
that we find this great movement now in the West to evangelize the Islamic world.
The weakness of the Muslims, the strength of the Western world and at the same time, this belief that the world is coming to an end within a matter of years
has created a situation of great danger and very dangerous implication for the Islamic world.
Now, what has changed?
Somebody might say; What's new about this?
Their missionaries have been coming to the Islamic world for centuries now; what's the big deal?
Well, there is a change.
And the change is, that the Christians have realized the failure of their previous strategies, and you'll see that in the video.
The Christians have realized that centuries of missionary work, whether to Muslims or non Muslims, have not brought them any results,
and so therefore they have to explain; Why is it, that their religion has not spread, if it is truth,
why is it, that people are not accepting it?
So they thought and they contemplated and they came up with this crazy idea.
Let me tell you what it is this.
They said, and therefore these people in the Islamic world have a pact, have a covenant, have an oath; with the devil.
And because of these satanic powers and principalities, so therefore we are unable to break these powers.
And so therefore, in order for us to do this, we must all gather together and pray.
We must all gather together and pray.
And it is through an intercession to Jesus that he will change and break the pact, so that we may enter into the Islamic world and open these people's hearts.
And of course, Allahسبحانه وتعالى tells us in his Qur'an
وَ مَا دُعٰٓؤُا الْكٰفِرِیْنَ اِلَّا فِیْ ضَلٰلٍ
That the prayer of the unbelievers goes astray, so no benefit, it is lost, because there's a prayer rooted in Shirk(شرک).
However though, they also in the tape as you will see shortly,
also explain what the other reason why they want to make these massive prayer call to evangelize Islamic world, through prayer.
and that is, they feel that if they enter into the issue of missionary work,
the average Christian, as you will see, you'll see a mother, an American mother, who is going to Bukhara(بخارا) or Tashkent(تاشقند) to give Tansih(تنصیح), to give Dawaah(دعوۃ) to Christianity.
They feel that if they can involve the average Christian in their cause, then they have a continuous financial backing for your causes.
And they say this is in tape;
that by involving we get a constant backing.
And you'll hear, they say to the words of the effect that when they see the sites, when they smell the smells, then they are attached to these countries forever.
So they will donate for missionary work in these countries forever.
And so therefore it brings me to my final couple points, and I won't hold you up, because I know you want to see the film.
The final point is that also the Christians have realized that the world is changing.
I mean, there is a deep demographic change in the world.
100 years ago, most people used to live in villages and outlying areas
because most of the world was agriculturally based.
I mean, people, how did they get their sustenance; How did they work?
Most of the peoples of the world, as long as it's 100 years ago, or even less, more than 50 years ago, before World War Two, the majority of the people lived off farms.
They lived in rural areas.
And so therefore, if you wanted to send missionaries, the target was to the outline areas, to the jungles to the far areas away from the cities, to the deserts and so forth.
But now the world is changing; there is a demographic change in the world, and this change is not unique only to the Islamic world,
but it is a phenomena which can be seen any part of the world, and that is, people are now concentrating in cities.
The people who farm are less now in the world.
And with that concentration in cities, not only in a number of small cities, but what are called mega cities, large metropolises, which hold millions and millions of human beings.
And so therefore, noticing this trend, what the Christians have done,
they decided that, okay, then, therefore we need to emphasize these major cities and try to get a foothold, indeed, even a toehold, in these cities,
for if we can get a portion of the city, we can establish a single church in the city,
then they've opened for themselves some sort of gate, some sort of door, some sort of window by which they can influence the events in those things.
So they've chosen 100 cities, and these are the 100 cities, or the 100 gateway cities, which they want to pray to.
Now finally, before we start, just have a couple things I want to say is that,
first of all, we should understand that this is not all missionary work.
We are talking about one missionary movement in the Islamic world.
And now let's talk about the video itself.
The video is aimed for Christians and was produced by Christians.
So in the video, there are going to be things which we recognize as Muslims to be Haram(حرام) in our religion.
We will hear a background music.
We will also see references to Eesaعلیہ السلام being the Lord of the world,
تَعٰلٰى ذلک عُلُوًّا كَبِیْرًا
You will also find biblical scripture quoted here and there.
But the idea is not that this movie was made by Muslims for Muslims.
This is Christian propaganda for Christians in order to encourage them to become, or support missionary work.
The other thing is that the movie has quite a lot of statements which are in innuendo, things which are not clear, but references.
So you really have to pay very close attention to the dialog.
And I really don't know, looking at the faces; I mean, how strong is the English in here, in the audience?
But anyway, if there are things which are being missed or are not being understood, I can stand by the screen and I can try to say quickly in Arabic,
if there's a need for but if the people feel comfortable with the English language, then they will just suffice with that.
I just might make every now and then myself or brother “Idrees(ادریس)” might say, pay attention to what they're saying here.
This is an important point, because we've seen this film, I mean time and time and time and again, so we basically remember.
So we know all the tricky points in it.
Anyway, not to hold you up very much longer, we'd like to start the film; It's 27 minutes, all right.
And then once we start, we'll have to the time we have some few other slides we'd like to talk about,
and then open it up for the brothers to take their questions and hear their comments.
And unfortunately, we couldn't convert it to color, so it's in black and white.
So my apologies again for that,
جزاکم اللہ خیر
The film starts off, giving you a very gloomy picture of the world without Christians.
So pay attention to the opening dialog; It's very important.
There are brothers in the back wish to come forward; There's some room here in the front.
Imagine a world without light, no churches, no Bibles, no Christians, a place where darkness envelops the nation.
We get a the sound trailer like this.
Look at the Happy Christian.
These are the faces in the 1040 Window.
Jesus died to bring them light.
You see, if the Muslims grow there, Muslim___
The 1040 Window encompasses a geographical region that stretches from 10 to 40 degrees north of the equator,
a belt spanning from North Africa through the Middle East to Eastern Asia.
Herein reside the overwhelming majority of the world's least evangelized people, almost 3 billion, about half the world's population, not nameless masses.
But individual souls passionately loved by God.
Today, the spiritual eyes of the church are riveted upon this final frontier of World Mission.
Okay, the spiritual eyes of church are riveted on this final frontier of World Missions.
Amplify within the 1041; Louise Bush serves as the international director of the A.D. 2000 and beyond movement.
This organization says; a church for every single Bible, where church for every people and the Gospel for every person by the year 2000.
The needs that are represented by the 1040 Window, if you look at a global perspective of need,
will be on a much higher level than the rest of the world.
Dr C Peter Wagner is one of the world's leading authorities on the 1040 Window.
He and his wife Doris, coordinate the United prayer track of the A.D. 2000 and beyond movement.
They diligently champion the cause, bringing the great spiritual, the physical needs, peoples to the forefront of awareness.
We believe that in the 1990s we are in the final trust of worthy evangelization.
In 250 years gospel has steadily spread across the world, so that Satan is now backed up into grass straw full, the testimony went.
People born outside the 1040 Window have a reasonable opportunity to hear the gospel in their lifetime
and to respond to a gospel message.
People born within the 1040 Window today do not.
In terms of poverty alone; the facts are overwhelming.
80% of the applicants are the poorest, within the 1040 Window.
It is no accident that the world's least evangelized cities are also its poorest with so much darkness concentrated in one area of the world.
The question remains, why?
Ed Silvoeso, a president of harvest evangelism;
That the very center of the 1040 Window is what we believe was the Garden of Eden?
You know, that was a place of the first fall.
That's where Satan got his first foothold, and then from there, he began to spread.
The results, every major non Christian religious system maintains its spiritual headquarters within the town.
Islam, Hinduism, Buddhism, Shintoism, Taoism, Sikhism, their followers drown in an ocean of spiritual deception.
They head towards a crisis.
Author and mission strategist George Otis Jr, views the darkness at the 1040 Window in terms of spiritual strongholds.
There have been pacts entered into in these areas between local populations and demonic powers that have existed for centuries, if not millennia.
This is like putting out a welcome mat to the enemy to enter a life or to enter a community.
Bangkok, Thailand, population over eight and a half million.
Its name means City of Angels, home of all the gods, Buddhism dominates all aspects of life.
Repetitive chants echo throughout temples as people worship and burn incense to Buddha.
Spirit houses stand in front of homes downtown office buildings and fancy high rise hotels.
People bring their offerings of food and flowers to appease the spirits and earn merit for the light to come.
Some wear amulets for protection and increased spiritual power.
The Buddhist belief in reincarnation spines them to an endless series of religious rituals with no hope for eternity.
Inspite of four centuries at Christian works, Das Christians comprise only 1% of the population.
Assemblies of God missionary built, prepared.
There are, I believe, principalities in powers over this land that make it very, very hard to reach with the gospel.
And these powers have never been broken in any real way.
You can walk to the street right now and talk to the people about Christ,
and they say, Oh yes, oh Christian is good and yes, your gospel is good.
But when you ask them to commit their life, we see the starvation
believing in Jesus Christ; they say, well, it's okay; We have a worldly reason.
Pastor Samna leads a small church at the edge of one of Bangkok's many slums.
1/5 of the population lives in the south.
This is the house and this is near everything.
This is a spirit house; It's like giving the honor to the lord of that area.
As we walked the squalid streets and alleys of this Bangkok slum, Pastor Samna showed us a glimpse of a society with value of human life.
Oh, she want us to see this.
Our hearts nearly broke when this drunken woman led us to her tiny hovel
she's asking me to pay this time.
We wonder if this beautiful baby boy will one day end up a statistic,
one of the estimated 35,000 street children who fall victim to the prostitution.
Obviously, as you can see, most the symbols are Western symbols.
Visitors are Western.
But they try to make it seem like that they clean these sins.
This situation, has earned the city its dubious reputation as the sin capital of Asia.
It also contributes to the rising scourge of AIDS.
World Health Authorities project that by the year 2000 approximately 4 million ties will be infected.
Despite years of ministry, attendance at pastor Samna church remains remarkably low.
Something is missing.
If people gather together and pray and ready together all the strong in this country,
the spirit quits control in this country, that would open the door for ____
get the thing that devils are controlling the country, thats why they are unsuccessful.
Director of Urban missions for youth with a mission John Dawson;
The United Person Saints; push back the canopy of oppression and cut off the operating authority of the powers of darkness in order to create optimum conditions for harvest.
Dick Eastman, president of every home for Christ.
The Lord Himself said, ask him it shall be given.
The implication, you don't ask, it's not given; In fact, you see in James, You have not because you ask not.
Dr Jerry Rankin, president of the Southern Baptist Foreign Mission Board;
Prayer is the greatest spiritual force that we have.
It's the mobilized prayer of God's people that will break down the strongholds of satan that will soften those hardened hearts.
John Robb World Vision International's director for unreached peoples;
Over and over again in the history of the church, breakthroughs among the unreached peoples and revival in the church have come about
because of bands of Christians who have united to pray.
A clarion call to prayer resounds around the world; millions of Christians unite their voices in one accord, the petition behind their prayers,
completing the Great Commission, reaching every nation, tongue and try with a good news of Jesus Christ.
What's happening now is that there's interest, commitment, involvement, prayer and focus on this part of the world.
And so the lights are beginning to go on where they have the darkness all these years.
October 1993, the United prayer track of the A.D. 2000 movement sponsors a grassroots prayer thrust called; Praying through the window.
That vision ignites a spark that blazes around the world.
For the first time in history, the global church unites in prayer.
Its focus, 62 of the world's least evangelized countries, the 1040 Window, over 21 million individuals from 905 countries answer on to pray.
In addition, over 250 prayer teams journey to the 1040 Window to intercede on site.
New Life church in Colorado Springs committed resources and personnel to help launch the prayer movement.
Ted Haggard pastors the church; One of the most significant things about this prayer movement is that it's broad based.
It includes Christians from practically every nation on earth and from certainly every theological perspective in the body of Christ.
And that's powerful and unprecedented, and it's huge.
It's not American, it's not Western, it's not Eastern, it's Christian.
See how they able to unite all their people upon on map.
October, 1995 this is just building on that momentum. The United prayer track launches praying through the window two the 100 gateway cities.
Michael little, president of the Christian Broadcasting Network, chairs this global prayer initiative.
The vision for praying for the 100 gateway cities is that we would mobilize over 50 million Christians to pray for breakthroughs; In these key cities.
And these are capital cities and these are strategically significant cities, politically and spiritually.
Cities are the greatest containers of people.
We have about 300 world class cities where over 40% of the human population live.
In a few years, it will be half the population of the earth that will live in a few mega cities and so this is defined the task.
Wherever we have large numbers of people, we're going to have demonic involvement.
There's an axiom here, demons are where people are.
They're interested in that which is freshest to God, and that's people.
That's why cities are the dark places that they are today.
Calcutta, India, population 13 and one half million, and rapidly growing.
The city derives its name from the Goddess Cali.
She represents the Earth Mother creator, but she manifests her evil side as the goddess of war, pestilence, blood, sacrifice and death.
Cords of villagers migrate to this city in search of a better life.
Instead, many end up joining the throng of more than 400,000 homeless people.
Calcutta ranks as the city with the world's lowest urban standard of living.
We desperately need to gain a place of spiritual authority in the mega cities of the world.
Play for ---- for we will not see harvest.
Jesus wept over his ----- God said prophets deceit is to spare them.
A critical part of praying through in the window two will be prayer journeys to each gateway city.
Project Coordinator, Mark Wilson of CBN, we're looking to have 10,000 intercessors praying on site in these 100 gateway cities,
we're also looking to have teams of worshippers, perhaps another 10,000 worshippers, going with the intercessors to be leading in worship and praise.
Prayer journey is a part of a growing trend to get Christians praying outside the walls of their church.
Steve Hawthorne has co authored a book on the subject.
A prayer journey in the 1040 Window can address all kinds of different prayer agendas, but most likely, the prayer agenda that God's giving us now is
the restraint, the curtailment of evil's long standing devices, just enough so that the people God's calling can wake up and respond to The Gospel.
To get a first hand glimpse of what it is like, let’s join the team on a prayer journey.
This group, from Chesapeake, Virginia, is preparing to go to the heart of the 1040 Window Central Asia.
Expectations are high, but so too are our apprehensions.
First of all, I'm a wife and mother, and so it's been hard for me to get out of that mom mode into that,
okay, now, guys, can you use me somewhere other than changing diapers?
I think the Lord is very close pray, and I think during this trip that he's going to really how kmow skills in me and that I can, I'll really walk away from this trip being able to hear the Lord.
For 10 days in country, this small group of Christians earnestly praise for the tremendous needs they see all around them.
Mostly, they welcome the presence of a board and invite him to establish an indigenous church among this unreached people.
Months later, from the comforts of home, they reflect on the trip with their team leader.
My tendency, I think, prior to the trip was to concentrate on my little family and the things that were going on in my life,
and I can't do that anymore with a clear conscience.
I'm really moved by the Spirit of God to become more global with my prayers.
We got there and we began with a sense that we were a part of something really important, like we were shredding a shroud.
My feeling was that we began to put a hole in the shroud, and now it's just ripping bigger and bigger, and so more light is shining in that land; because of our prayers,
There's an urgency to this mission of reaching the nations with the gospel,
so that we may partner with God and ushering we return Jesus; That's important stuff.
New Life Church in Colorado Springs sent 30 people on a prayer journey during the first 1040 Window prayer thrust.
Pastor Ted Haggard speaks from experience;
It's a seed to get the average Christian, or even the above average Christian, the great intercessor, onto a field outside of their own world, is always worth it,
because once they see the sights, smell the smell and pray over a region,
they'll finance evangelism there, all the rest of their own.
They looked upon whole cities through the lenses of God's promises, and they're marked with a hope that won't go away.
People rise with ambition to that which they hope for.
Intercessors do indeed represent the trip wire of change.
Who are the intercessors that are praying for the 1040 Window?
Nameless people, people that we've never heard of,
faithful grandmothers and students and persecuted pastors and lay leaders around the world have shouldered up the miracles that we've seen in the 1040 Window.
Children are jumping on board, and I just have the idea that God answers kids prayers quicker.
Frontiers associates in Mesa, Arizona recognizes a value of mobilizing children with a vision for World Missions.
Through the work of Jill Harris and others, they are breaking the next generation for the harvest.
Prayer; how to do ------
these children they are committed to prayer for this 1040 Window, and these cities in a 1040 Window,
they're going to be committed to further prayer; They're going to be committed to going
It's the heartbeat of God from Genesis chapter 12, when he called the Abraham as his first cross cultural missionary.
And behind that wonderful promise there, he said, you all the peoples of there will be blessed,
find that beam throughout the Old and New Testaments and Jesus picks it up, of course, in the Great Commission
and reaffirms the Abrahamic covenant.
He says, Go and make disciples of all the peoples on the face of the earth.
Historically, the growth of the church worldwide can be measured by its level of obedience to this biblical mandate.
Global reports clearly demonstrate that God is moving mightily in response to his people as they pray, give and go.
It's God's time for harvest; There's no doubt about that.
But also, in the last 10 years, where this momentum has come, you've seen the greatest increase in United prayer that has ever happened.
The world has never before witnessed a revival like, what is currently, he plays with nations.
Brother Andrew has 40 years of missionary, smuggling Bibles to the suffering underground church.
I am one of the few missionaries in the world, who has seen this dream come true.
I could gone borders open, you could go in with Bibles openly, freely.
It's a totally new one ------- .
Even within the 1040 Window Excel, pockets of Hope exist.
New Christians set free from the religious heritage of their culture; Now worship and praise the living God.
This thriving church in Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia sees many converts.
Pastor, Prince Guna Ratnam of Calvary Church.
When they become Christians, it means something to them, because their parents are either Buddhist or Hindus,
so they go ---- for persecution.
I was very fearful of my father because he was very strict, especially on religion.
I just cannot make any of my own choice.
What happened to ReconKhar, who chose to follow Jesus against the wishes of a Sikh father?
He was very angry with me, and for two years he didn't actually speak to me.
In my case, I could never convince my father, it was so difficult.
I prayed, and I said, God, you do something supernatural.
So he must know that this is the true living God, true enough.
After two years, he had a dream, and one day he comes in the morning and tells me that I think the god you're worshiping is a true God.
Reports from mainland China describe the nominal threat in the numbers of new believers set.
90% of these Christians belong to house churches scattered throughout the entire country.
10s of 1000s of new converts are added to the church daily.
Thomas Wong, chairman of the A.D. 2000 and beyond Movement grew up in Beijing.
The Chinese church at the beginning was very, very tiny, very small, very immature.
The God has allowed the Chinese churches to go through several trials of fire.
And the blood of the martyrs is always a seed of the cost.
Bob Shogren, president of frontiers associates, we are seeing things happen in an unprecedented scale in the Muslim world
that have never happened in the history of missions of Islam.
In fact, more Muslims have come into the Lord in the past 25 years than in the entire history of missions Islam,
my soul lied the grass needed the water.
Two years, one of a growing number of former Muslims who recognize Jesus Christ as their Lord and Savior.
This young man from Morocco is another for security reasons; He chooses to remain anonymous.
Christianity was presented to me, not as a local religion.
It was presented to me through the testimony of believers as life, as truth.
It's a living experience of the living God, especially Muslim belief in visions and dreams.
Maybe you can pray for them; God can work miracles in your life, and I feel like I am part of that miracle, somebody praying for me.
Increasing openness to the Gospel has led to increased persecution.
The swelling tide of Islamic fundamentalism threatens the church with ------- with three Iranian Azure, that fall is risen with, banded in martyrdom,
once again, the seeds of the gospel are planted in the blood of the martyrs,
rather than giving up on these extremists;
Brother Andrew reminds us of the Christian way.
Fundamentalists are desperate people; Terrorists are desperate people, and desperate people are, by nature, always open to the redeeming message of Jesus Christ.
Jesus will come back when we see the fulfillment of the Great Commission.
He said that this gospel of the Kingdom shall be preached to all nations as a custom, added to the whole world, and then the end shall come.
Virgil Amos, Director of ambassadors fellowship, an organization committed to mobilizing minorities to world missions.
I think it's now or never. We have a chance right now to do what God has called us to do, and if we do not take the challenge, we will pass up, our opportunity.
I believe that this generation, barring any kind of massive disobedience, will be the generation on station time when the Lord Jesus Christ returns to claim that which rightfully
Fred lunches, Director of the Youth with the missions global frontiers, explains,
we have all the money necessary; We have all the resources; We have communications technology like never before, transportation technology like never before.
We have everything it takes.
We just need to mobilize the church to take what it has and move out towards the final frontiers.
Is totally possible.
The zeal of the lord of hosts is going forth the power of the Holy Spirit; Now we need to pray for the laborers.
What will it take to receive race condition?
It all boils down to simple obedience on the part of the church.
Pat Robertson, founder and chairman of the Christian Broadcasting Network;
Go you into all the world and teach all nations, teaching them to observe all things whatsoever I have commanded you.
And learn always, even unto the end of the age.
So this is what we have been told to do.
And if we're going to be obedient to our Lord, we will follow his command.
We must put a priority on staying focused.
There are many good things that we can get sidetracked into and some awful things that we get sidetracked into,
and we must be vigilant and very diligent about being focused on doing what God has called us to do.
Said; Challenge to fulfilling the Great Commission comes from within the body of Christ.
I think this is part of what Satan wants to do, is to let the church sleep and take care of itself and say, we have needs here.
Why should we be concerned with others?
What we need is an impartation.
We need God to touch us now and to change our heart and to give us his heartbeat.
Prayer is a way of getting on God's wavelength, sharing his heart as Bob Pierce, the founder of World Vision, said,
Let my heart be broken with the things that break the heart of God.
And in prayer, we sense God's heartbeat,
all that land within history, within the days of time, receives a reward of the suffering.
It's that passion that is welling up within our hearts with the jealousy that any price is cheap to see if the Son of God is followed,
and soon every people on the earth.
What is the reward of Christ's suffering?
March for Jesus Director Tom Pelton;
As we come closer to the fulfillment of this great commission,
I think that we're going to have an even, even greater revelation of why we've been doing this all along.
It's that this mass of humanity from every nation, tribe and language would come before Him and would worship Him and acknowledge that he is Jesus and that He is Lord.
The end result of our evangelism and things that we do is that Jesus would receive glory and worship and praise.
It's that time in history where God is is gathering all peoples to himself.
------ and if everybody in nervous; Let's get this done for the Son of God.
Hello. I'm Michael little. This October, millions of Christians worldwide will be praying for the 100 gateway cities of the 1040 Window.
I want to invite you personally to participate in what could be the most significant prayer movement in the history of the church.
Just a moment, you'll see a phone number and an address that you can call or write for more information,
we have prayer materials available to help you become strategically involved in God's plan for reaching all nations with the gospel.
Prayer is the spark that will light the 1040 Window join us in clang to the window for the 100 gateway cities.
Okay, before we start, have been asked that the brothers who are standing please go to the masjid extension on this floor.
Sound and picture is relayed over there.
So please, for those brothers who are standing in the back, You've been requested to go to the masjid extension,جزاک اللہ.
I like we all saw that 27 minutes.
And you know, I mean, we all laugh when we hear these Christian comments that, you know, imply Shirk(شرک) or they're dancing and so forth.
And that's not the point here.
I mean, the point here is not to expose their ignorance of Allah, their Shirk(شرک) and so forth, because I think we are all aware of that.
The point here is that let us look at how they are focused upon their aims.
I don't think it is necessary for an audience like this, for me to recite verses from the Qur'an or statements from the Prophetﷺ, Sunnah(سنۃ),
or provide you examples of how the earliest Muslims came together upon their religion.
I think all of us are aware of that to some degree or the other.
But there is a difference here.
A difference is that we have this true message of Islam.
We have the guidance of Allah.
We have the Sunnah(سنۃ) of the Prophetﷺ.
We have the way of our earliest predecessors, our Salaf(سلف) and yet we are an unfocused people.
We are a divided people; We are a lazy people, and we expect Allah to give us Victory.
We all know that Islam, in the end, will have victory.
This is no doubt.
Allah has told us this in His book, and the Prophetﷺ has informed us this in his Sunnah(سنۃ),
but that only one Muslim is converted to Christianity; This is a shame upon us.
And for them to be able to enter into our lands with such focus, with such power and such abilities,
is a clear indication that we are not doing our duty, that we are not doing our duty.
I don't know if you realize when you're watching the film, how many organizations you saw, every single person being interviewed was from a different organization.
And yet, we find Muslims today having organizations of 3, 4 people,
and they wonder if they are should unite with their other brothers, who are just consisting of 3, 4, 5, 10 people,
and they said, they argue; They always ask question after question.
Ya Sheikh, are we to work with other Muslims, who carry the same belief as us, who carry the same way as us?
Let us, I mean, there are many lessons to be drawn.
I want this just to of course, remember just a couple points that I pointed out at the beginning before we started.
I came up with few more comments; I guess we could open it up for questions.
The issue of I guess you heard at the end of the lecture where the gentleman said that we must put a priority on staying focused.
There are many good things that we can get sidetracked into and some awful things that we can get sidetracked into.
We must be vigilent, and very diligent about being focused on doing what God has called us to do.
And also, I want you to remember the other statement that came just before that, when the person said, we have all the money necessary.
We have all the resources.
We have communication technology like never before, transportation technology like never before.
We have everything it takes; We just need to mobilize the church to take what it has and move out to the final frontiers.
Now we are need for the laborers.
And likewise, I want you to remember the statement made by George Otis, one of the major people who are behind this thing around the world,
where George Otis said that barring any major disobedience, that this is that he feels that this is the generation which is going to be on stage with return of Jesus Christ.
And this ties in with their millennium belief.
I mean, we have to understand what are the ideas and what are the forces that are moving them?
We also we want to use to give you an example some of the follow up.
I mean, the last prayer movement, which was in October of last year, 1995 when we first came across this information, myself and brother “Idrees”
had 105 million people; I guess they said, 105 million people.
I mean, even if this, let's say this is an exaggeration, they didn't meet their target of 105 million people.
But we're out just to gain 20 million people, or 10 million people focus on one thing.
I mean, this shows, what kind of organizational skills they have and what type of you know, ability they have to mobilize their Christian people for this matchup.
And to give you an example, some of the follow up they've been regularly sending,
brother “Idrees”, he's sending me some of these magazines,they've been sending you everything goes in his name right in my head.
So here, this is one of their magazines, of course, entitled front lines, which they put out monthly, which gives you a follow up on some of the global activity to bring their Deen(دین) to the Muslims.
And of course, here, of course, they're even extending it to the political realm, where they're showing how this is extending to so called peace process.
And of course, the image itself speaks 1000 words with the fact of it being a Muslim girl on the cover.
Additionally, rather they have placed certain sites on the Internet, where nowadays, of course, they are using modern technology to spread their message
in which they have numerous sites, they literally have dozens of sites on the Internet,
which they use, which bring people who have computer access can literally get additional information, where they also have sites,
which you can purchase some of their missionary brochures and other material which they can which person can use in order to bring the Gospel to Jesus, as they sale to Muslims.
More so they show basically some of their goals for this coming year, where they say 1996 is at a year of boldness.
And just to give us very brief example, they state that one of their target areas now, of course, is Albania.
They said this spring in Albania. They said, we'll expand our blitz to reach even more souls for Christ.
So he here you have Albania, which originally, of course, was a Muslim land,
and rather the Christians in this sense, of course, are focusing in on this land for their as one of their major goals for the coming year.
I like you to serve read some statistics to you, because I mentioned to you earlier that this is just one movement,
and there are 1000s of Christian groups which have their own movement.
So let's just read some statistics; I take it from 1991, I photocopied this from the International bulletin of missionaries, which is a magazine that comes out quarterly.
It just tells people where it involves the missionary work of what's going on and how they act to it.
For instance, again, besides the world population, they say the metropolises, which are the cities that over have over 100,000 people in the world, are 3500
and the mega cities of over 1 million population, you heard him say about the mega cities of the world, or 340 in the year 1991,
okay then they go on to the different amounts of Christians and religions and so forth, and they break it up by continent and so forth.
But let's get to the Christian organizations; that there are 21,300 services or agencies.
I mean agencies that go out and do services like medical and so forth, charity, relief work.
21,300 foreign mission sending agencies, 4050
and they have how many institutions?
99,580 institutions to teach the people.
What about Christian workers?
The amount of workers through out that they have from all nationalities, from all the different denominations, in 1991 was 3,980,700 throughout.
3,980,000
How much is the total amount of giving to Christian causes per year?
1059 billion.
Which is what; 1 trillion; I don't know if you use the word trillion in England.
In America would be $1 trillion.
1059 billion and also in terms of the income of global foreign missions, it's $8.9 billion in 1991,
$8.9 billion!
By the technology strike they have, look how many computers are used by Christians in their organizations.
82,600 computers are used by them.
This is very strong, you know, resource for them; For their Dawah(دعوۃ), they have 82,600 resources.
How many new titles they produce per year.?
22,600 new titles are published every year.
And how many periodicals they have, how many magazines they have?
24,900 magazines.
How many articles and books, just about the subject of evangelization, are produced per year?
11,500 books and articles are written in terms of evangelization.
How many Bibles they distribute per year.?
They distribute 553 million Bibles per year
and the new testament, without the old testament; They distribute another 18 million of that.
How many radio TV stations they have?
2340 Radio TV stations for evangelization purposes.
And how many listeners do they have?
The monthly on these radio stations, they believe that about 1.4 billion people listen monthly to either radio, television to pick up these broadcasts,
and then now, yeah, that's basically the major in statistics.
So you can see, I mean, right now, this is from 1991 what might it be in the 1996,
and now the great emphasis you heard over and over and saying, The Great Commission, has come to an end.
In other words, they feel that this is a time for harvest, because after the harvest comes a time for war.
And let me guarantee you, brothers and sisters, that if this is the resources, where the times of peace,
we just might imagine what it might be the resource when it comes to time for war.
I guess we wanted to show some of the slides before we just give us five more minutes; I know there's probably a lot of questions.
So if you just saw some of the overheads, to give you some ideas about the different threats they feel.
You know, when they have these prayer meetings, or the prayer points they have for their intersection, they mention few prayer points.
And these are the things which they're emphasizing and you can sort of get an idea what the strengths they see for themselves and also one of the dangers, they see them for themselves.
This is an idea of the 1040 Window.
And these are the 100 mega cities you can see, of course, Mecca there and major cities in the Islamic world,
but this is their window that they want to focus on.
Probably a lot of brothers here from North Africa; So you can see that this is like from their book.
I think of this book, 100 gig with cities.
They sort of focus a map on North Africa; Let's take an example of a city.
Okay, this is the capital of Mauritania, and look at the prayer point.
Okay, first one, pray that the Islamic Sharia(شریعہ) law would be overturned.
So this shows that they have a very big concern about the implementation of Sharia(شریعہ).
They see that as a danger and obstacle for them.
Also for report claim that Christian humanitarian relief; the idea about using relief work in order to spread Christianity.
And also pray for radio broadcast in the Hassaniya(حسنیۃ) language of Arabic, or the “Hassaniyan(حسنیۃ) Dialog”.
And also pray for the translation of the Bible in this language.
In other words, because they are focused even on the various self label groups that the people have.
This is again Casablanca, Morocco and again, that they asked, like a number 3 pray for increasing numbers, radius of the broadcast
Until they will be able to receive correspondence material by mail.
So again, it shows that they have already, right now, some sort of effort and they're praying for its increase, means there must be something there that they're praying for to increase.
Here's “Banjul” in Gambia.
And again, look at the number point number 6, praying that the three Sufi brotherhoods would come to base their fellowship in the Holy Spirit.
So, I mean, I know that sounds very, you know, funny, but the point is that they realize that Sufism is a door for them to missionary work,
because that's Sufism or Tasawuf(تصوف) is based in shirk.
And so therefore it's just not much for person, to leave worshiping of a saint to worshiping of a prophet.
And so therefore they want to base the Sufi orders in the Holy Spirit.
Number one, I pray that the Church will reach out the Muslim majority, particularly the Mandingo people.
This is a throwback the issue of slavery in the United States, and has its implications.
If you understand the issue of slavery, and the roots will be United States.
Again, Al-Jazair(الجزائر), the point there in the middle Islamic fundamentalists had gained more political power.
This is a big thing they want to bring down; So they're afraid of this.
And again, that the issue of that fundamentalism is anti women.
So the first point, pray for the Muslim women as more Islamic laws are placed on them.
In other words, that Islam is, by its nature, anti women.
And so therefore you can see that there's a focus on women in particular,
and also about the fundamentalist number three are seeking to install a government similar to the Iranian Islamic State.
Again, this is another fear of their's in Islamic government,
Okay; Cairo; Cairo(قاہرہ), another example, if you can look at number three and Al Azher(الازہر) is the largest Islamic University in the world,
and sends out hundreds of Islamic missionaries, annual, hundreds!,
Of course, while they have 69,000 per year, we have hundreds.
This is our large institution.
Pray that the students will be disillusioned with Islam and turn to Christ.
So the point is, is that they understand that I mean, even though it's as an institution, is nothing comparable to what they have in terms of resources,
but still, those 100 missionaries pose a threat.
So they're hoping that they are turned to Christ.
Then now we have the Middle East, of course,
and these are the cities, 22 cities that they want to focus.
22 of the 100 cities are in the Middle East.
Starts off with Mecca, Riyadh, Sana’a, Muscat, Abu Dhabi, you can search of read the list.
Okay in Mecca again, there's a problem, you know,
In fact; and we talked about the fact that the Kaaba(کعبہ) as it's one of the signs proving the truth of the Prophet, Prophet of Mohammedﷺ.
So then they may say; look at it in this way, place of the Kaaba(کعبہ), the mystical powers behind it would be bound from captivating millions of Islamic souls.
So in other words, they say there must be some sort of satanic power behind it.
Why would people go through this desolate area and so forth?
Then point number two, pray that the Muslims performing the annual Hajj would be disappointed with the commercialism of the city.
So in other words, the indication here is that consumerism and materialism causes a spiritual crisis.
And now that consumerism and materialism has entered the Islamic world, that even the Hajj, and whoever has been to Hajj has noticed that
this might open them a room for Christian evangelical work.
Then over here, they say, for the Islamic religious leaders and religious beliefs that they would have miraculous conversions, like paul on the road of Damascus.
Paul for those of you don't know, is an enemy fighting Eesa Ibn Maryam(عيسٰى ابن مریم) and then all of a sudden, on the road to Damascus,
he supposedly saw Eesa(عيسٰى) who chose him as the first apostle of his
and of course, he's the one who was a Jew who really changed much of the Christian teachings.
And then, of course, pray number four, that the royal family will allow Christians to work, reside and worship openly Mecca.
And they find it's very important for them to have a foothold in the Islamic world, and especially cities like Mecca,
i.e. in Gaza in Palestine
Look at number two, a pray, the increased average from the house of like, bookstore.
So they got a bookstore in Gaza, they want to pray that stronger.
I mean, the point is that you might say, Well, what's a bookstore?
But to them, they see a single bookstore in a city as a place for them to start their work.
And then also number six pray, the Christian social work done in Gaza would effectively demonstrate the love of Christ the most important
Again the issue of social work as a means for them to manipulate Muslim minds and then make evangel to us.
Kuwait City, I guess we want to come down to the bottom.
Number five; Pray that Kuwaiti money will never again be used to propagate Islam by building mosques, burying Bibles and paying for Islamic conversions.
I don't know of any Duaat(دعوات) will actually, you know, pay for people to convert to Islam.
But the point is, they can see a threat that Islamic work done in places like Kuwait which is probably among the most country which generally donates to Islamic causes.
You would see this come to an end.
Abu Dhabi, We have, of course, about the hospitals, right?
Number four? Yeah, pray that the people would see Christ love demonstrated by the Christian Medical agency serving here.
So again, the use of medicine
For that Vinyls Radio Broadcast literature would bear fruit in evangelizing all people.
In Central Asia, again, I show you the cities of the 1040 windows up from Pakistan down to India.
Number one, pray that those who practice fock Islam; worshiping the city's patron saint would hear the good news of Jesus Christ.
So in other words, it's not much for a person to go from worshiping one man to worshiping another man from going from Saint worship to Prophet worship.
Kazakhstan also they have. What do we have in Kazakhstan?
Many Islamic nations are trying to influence Kazakhstan and pressure to restrict Christian witness;
Christian witness means Christian Dawah(دعوۃ) is growing; The gospel would not be restricted.
And then pray for the Bible Society office number 5 that has recently opened, the entire Bible will be translated into Kazakh.
In India,“Patna” and notice that number two in India, 9 out of 10 Muslims who convert to Christianity revert back to Islam.
So I know, but look at the point that the family community pressure is too strong.
Pray to the church will provide strong support and fellowship when Muslims start to cry.
So in other words, they realize they have made mistake,
the sense that in the past, you just give them Dawah(دعوۃ), and now they want to solve the problem, do it as a complete person and give social support.
So by a person, the person will not feel compelled, because he feels outcast, to return back to Islam.
Also, of course, pray that strike between Muslims and Hindus would cause disillusionment, meaning that the true preset peace,
in other words, and you can see how the political implication of that is that they could use Civil War
and the strive and the tiredness in people occur after that as a means for them to spread their message.
Okay, finally got to Eastern Asia and you can see it goes from Japan, China and down to Malaysian Indonesia,
and also, as you saw in the video, was Indonesia was shown in Malaysia.
In Kualalampur; Pray that they get a spirit of superstition among the Malays,
who employed the surface of the local BOMA, or spirit images, to deal with spiritual issues.
So again, they notice that the influence of this type of focus on and how this is important in them,
I mean, they understand that the true Towheed(توحید) Is not in these countries, and how these are keys for them.
And also notice number of 2.
Divorce is a common element in Malaysian society.
So social unrest, they see it is also another opportunity for them for their message.
And 3, that government restrictions against evangelizing have lifted.
As the guy said on the video, when a person converts, he's either Hindu or Sikh.
But then later on in the video, he saw a Muslima(مسلمہ).
The church leaders say that he does evangelization work to Muslims to Malays because it's legal.
But the example they give you, of course, of a Muslim one, only later on.
And here we have Brunei, number 1;
Yes; pray Christian literature may be important in the context before Christians be allowed.
And also, number 4, a Sultan better turn the whole country, towards Islam,
afraid that the God would soften the heart of the current Sultan on allow his position to turn to Christ.
No but the point is, they can understand there that in some countries, a single man can change the people so they can take the mind of one man.
They can do a lot of work.
And what do we have? We have Jakarta Indonesia.
Again, if you look at number 6, explains of the rise of Islam,
they're concerned together with the rise of Islam, fundamentalist Islam, and so forth.
Another idea,
Okay, this is one for just example of predominantly non Muslim city, Xian in China, which is 59% non religious, atheists
and the Muslims are only 1.4% of the city.
However, look at what is number 5.
Pray the city's Muslim Quarter might be reached to the gospel.
So the fact that they, you know, even the 1.4% of the city is Muslim,
yet they have listed their prayer points, one of the major prayer points at the crave the Muslim corner.
And that's indicative that you know the what you saw about the Hindus and the Sikh and so forth really is not their main aim,
but their main aim is, and always will remain the religion of Islam and fighting Islam,
because this is, as has said by many Western philosophies,
the question of the world, which of these two faiths are the true faith, and this is how history will come to its final conclusion, as both we and they recognize.
And this is an example only of the chart where they had for the 30 days last October, or 31 days of October
where they had the different cities they were praying for each day.
And of course, each day they tried to mobilize 105 million people.
And as I said, even if they mobilized only 10 million people to pray, it shows the strength of their organization, their ability to mobilize people for the cause.
We will have one more slide and let it open up for questions, because we are very close to Ishaa(عشاء).
This is an idea of the various American businesses which support Christian evangelical work.
This is from something else, why I was taken from this series, or from another thing we took.
And if you notice incorporation who make cheese.
Let other things here, American Express, American Airlines, Quakers said there's Microsoft somewhere around here, under M come down there, Microsoft Corporation,
and a few other things you might notice. CRW, Unisys Corporation, my old employers, Quakers, quality in, airlines and so forth.
Philip Morris, Pepsi Company Foundation Incorporated.
So all these organizations are donating money; These are businesses, and they're not Christian businesses; They're secular businesses,
but yet they still donate their money to missionary war.
I guess we can take a few questions because I'll never coming right After Salah(صلاۃ).
And we don't want to pull the brothers and sisters up any further.
And I just have one comment, somebody might say, well, okay, what does one have to do, Muslims in the West,
and that's a bad situation; We need to focus on here; Well.
One of the organizations which you saw in the video has also come up with thing focused on photocopy a letter from Congress, understanding, responding to Islam, witnessing to Muslims in America.
And I found that in the last two years, they've written three books in terms of doing missionary work to the Muslims in the United States.
And I would imagine that there's probably a number of books that have been written, or on the way to be written to be concerning missionary work among the Muslims of the United Kingdom.
Okay, he says, your lecture is quite a revelation for us in London.
However, seems typical American inspired Christianity to like funds, enrich themselves, as happened in the past.
I think this is one of them; We should not be negligent, but not alarmed.
Islam is increasing more than ever in history of mankind.
I guess that's true; But I mean, at the same time we're also facing I mean, we should not be alarmed.
And no one is saying here that, you know that tomorrow Islam is going to come to an end.
Of course, not.
Allahسبحانه وتعالى  said in His Qur'an,
هُوَ الَّذِیْۤ اَرْسَلَ رَسُوْلَهٗ بِالْهُدٰى وَ دِیْنِ الْحَقِّ لِیُظْهِرَهٗ عَلَى الدِّیْنِ كُلِّهٖ وَ لَوْ كَرِهَ الْمُشْرِكُوْنَ۞
As He, Who has sent His messenger with the guidance in the true religion to manifest it above all religions; Even the disbelievers dislike that.
So that Islam will be the final religion, and that all people enter to Islam as the Prophetﷺ said
that the “MULK(ملک)” of his Ummah(امۃ), or the sovereignty of his Ummah(امۃ) reach whatever night and day reach.
So this is a fact, I mean, without doubt.
But the point is that the political situation now in the Islamic world and given the technology resources they have present us with a challenge that we haven't faced before,
and also given the weakness of the Dawah(دعوۃ) so forth.
I mean, this shouldn't make us despair, but what we should do is, we should redouble our efforts in order to face this type of challenge.
What is the basic Dawa(دعوۃ) of the Christians used to lead Muslims astray?
Okay, I'll give you an example.
This is one booklet; Unfortunately we weren't able to blow it up for you.
One of their arguments is that Muslims worship something called the moon god.
And I know this sounds very ridiculous and, you know, we probably laugh it off.
But given the Islamic ignorance, the ignorance that there is in the Islamic world,
this might be, you know, plausible to a lot of Muslims who are ignorant of Arabic and ignorance to the religion.
So you'll give a little cartoon here; It's very easy reading of a person,
an Arab dressed up in Arab guard and an American and his son come to the mosque and say,
with his son asked him, What are they doing, daddy?
They're praying to their moon god, sir.
And he says, moon god, wait, he'll get my sword and kill you, and so forth.
And then it goes to a whole description of how the word Allah is means moon god, and so forth.
And then finally, the Muslim weeps in tears as he understands that Jesus has come to save him
and to show you a picture which is supposed to be the Prophetﷺ burning in hell.
And then they go on to about how the Christian, the Muslim, who has just been converted, says, I must tell my people about the moon god
and about the glorious Christ who saves sinners and is coming soon again the emphasis of the you know, Millennium and so forth.
The guy, the American says to him, it may cost your life.
And then the Arab says, it will be worth it, because I will be with my loving Father in heaven for all eternity,
so that I'm willing even to die for this cause.
I mean the implication of violence and so forth is there.
This is just one example of what they do.
In the Qur'an it is mention that Eesaعلیہ السلام coming back here in millennium?
I know He doesn't mention this.
The Prophetﷺ told us that Eesaعلیہ السلام will come down.
He told us when you'll come down, that will come near the end of time, when the Muslims will be under the leadership of the Mahdi(مہدی),
arrayed to fight the Antichrist, the King of the Jews,
that Eesa(عيسٰى) will come down in Damascus with his hands on two angels side, on either side of him, and that he will come down before Salat-al-Fajr(صلاۃ الفجر),
and that the Muslims will leave him, tell him to lead us in prayer.
And Eesa(عيسٰى) will say, No,
وَإِمَامُكُمْ مِنْكُمْ
your Imam is from you.
And then the battle will start; and then Eesa عليه السلام will kill the Antichrist, the King of the Jews, with his spear, and show his blood to the Muslims.
And then the Muslims will have the general slaughter of the Jews.
And so much so the Jews will flee to the rock and tree will say,
یا عبداللہ، یا مسلم
Oh Muslim(مسلم), Oh Abdullah(عبدللہ)! There’s a Jew behind me, come and kill him.
And then will come the other signs like that Eesa Ibn Maryam(عيسٰى ابن مریم) will put an end to Christianity, as the Prophetﷺ said;
that he would break the cross and exterminate the pig and drop the Jizya(جزیہ),
then the signs of (یاجوج ماجوج), Gog and Magog.
And then finally, he will rule upon the Ummah(امۃ) and die and will be buried in this Ummah(امۃ).
So this is these details have been all mentioned in great detail concerning the return of Eesaعلیہ السلام.
However, the issue about when is it in Millennium or not?
There's nothing in the Qur'an or the Sunnah(سنۃ) to indicate that.
What is the Jewish position; I mean, the anti Christian and the anti Muslim.?
Have they got a global plan or what is your opinion about it?
I think I spoke about this in some detail last week at the Asian center.
But anyway, I mean the Jews, you know, manipulate situations, and so therefore, when they manipulate Christian hatred to the Muslims for their own aims,
and the Christians manipulate the Jews, the Jews for their own aims also.
Is there any connection between Freemason and the 1040 Window?
Allah knows best if there's any connection.
And we shouldn't go further than what the facts we see.
I mean, let's not try to get into a lot of conjecture, and a lot of, you know conspiracy theories and so forth.
We have people who have means that have a message and are trying to convert Muslims, and so let's deal with it at that level.
And if here are connections between Freemasonry and so forth, we can deal with that when we get to that juncture.
Has the time come for Muslims to unite and set aside their differences?
Could you see a police say words the brothers and sisters, who call to their respective groups and wage war on the Muslims for other groups and unite to serve Islam.
Yes, of course it's time to unite.
And of course it's time to put aside our differences is Allah سبحانه وتعالى  says in His Qur'an
وَتَعَاوَنُوْاعَلَى الْبِرِّوَالتَّقْوٰى ۪ وَلَاتَعَاوَنُوْاعَلَى الْاِثْمِ وَالْعُدْوَانِ۪
That we come together upon righteousness and fearing of ALLAH, do you not assist one another in sinfulness and aggression towards one another.
And however, Allahسبحانه وتعالى has told us,
وَاعْتَصِمُوْا بِحَبْلِ اللّٰهِ جَمِیْعًا وَّلَاتَفَرَّقُوْا۪
That we come together and hold all of us to the rope of Allah, and that we do not split.
So therefore we have to hold to the rope of Allah; So we need to hold to the Book, the Sunnah(سنۃ), the way the earliest Muslims, and not split from that.
As far as gathering Muslims in a hodgepodge way, that's not going to solve the problem.
And likewise, this incessant, you know, splitting off and not tolerating differences, when the Sharia(شریعہ) itself permits the toleration of differences,
this also will not serve the Ummah(ٓمۃ).
We must not, neither go to the one extreme of trying to gather people under any banner,
and also the other extreme of neglecting when the Sharia(شریعہ) allows us to overlook differences.
Okay, a letter came from Albania to our brother in Britain, which says,
“We are flowers with good smell. We need some water. If we don't have it, we will dry out and we will die.
So when Muslim missionaries went to Albania, they found the Christians giving Muslims TV, satellite and money to convert them to Christianity.”
Thank you for this information.
It's very useful.
And again, this shows the urgency and the problem we are facing.
May Allah reward the person put forth that information!
How can the Muslims counter such a huge plan like that the Christians, which you have showed today?
By beginning with ourselves.
You know the Prophetﷺ was one time asked a concerning a vice, and the Prophetﷺ said,
قُلْ آمَنْتُ بِاللهِ ثُمَّ اسْتَقِمْ
say, I believe in Allah and then be upright.
The first way we can counter this christianary work or Christian missionary work, or Jewish plots and plans, or whatever challenge we face is by being true believers,
at being truly upright upon the religion of Islam, as Prophetﷺ told us.
Brother, why don't you distribute the materials you presented and help us to confront their ways by another lecture or a series of lectures?
Okay, as a versus this distribution of the material, my personal feeling is that I don't like to see this material distributed to a large body of Muslims
because it does can contain Shubhaat(شبہات) or things which might confuse the average Muslim.
And so therefore this should not be put in the hands of the Muslims.
As far as a series of lectures, one of the purposes behind this lecture is that I'm, we're working this year.
We usually have a yearly project that myself and brother “Idrees” tried to do.
And one of the yearly project this year is to try to least add something to the Islamic library regarding missionary work.
And the idea is to have a book in the English language which people can use in non Arabic speaking countries.
Because when we were in China last year on Beijing, China for the United Nations Conference on Women,
we noticed that a lot of Muslim groups from the non Arab speaking world came to us and complained concerning missionary activity, that's really what started this issue.
And so therefore, but however, they do not have resources.
So the idea now is that we're hoping to gather some material which is very prevalent in Arabic language,
translate it, organize it in a way which we feel which will be useful for people, and then give it to whoever wants to distribute it
and publish it in the Islamic world, so that Muslims who are incharge of organizations or incharge of Masajid(مساجد),
and do not speak Arabic will have at least some resources to help them counter this missionary effort
and also to raise public awareness, as we've done this evening, or at least as we hope we do get this evening in all of this best.
Which site?
ﷺhich site on the internet can use to find the information.
The site is “http://www.aims.org”
and I can write it down for the brothers here in Muntadha and whoever wants to get it from them afterwards can just copy it down.
Question number four is my aunt, who is a missionary traveling back and forth to Gambia and has adopted 105 Muslim children over the past five years in Gambia.
And it is part of the organization.
The organization stated to me that if Islam is so great, why don't we have missionaries like they do, giving practical help to the people.
I did not have an answer.
I mean, what can we do in terms of this thing?
It's a sadness that brings this, but it's a part of our division.
And also this is a punishment from Allahسبحانه وتعالى, due to our sinfulness.
When people are sinful, Allah punishes them, and one of the ways Allah punishes people is by not allowing them to worship Him, because that increases them in sin.
And as I said, by the Salaf(سلف) that a sin leads to another sin, and we can see the situation.
Okay, the brother says, Sheikh, the little booklet that you have showed about the moon guy has already reached East London.
So please remind the Muslims that Evangelization is not just in America, but it also happening here.
Yes, it's also, I'm sure was happens here.
And it's upon the Muslims of this city to see how they can see what type of arguments they are using to convince, or to try to convince Londoners, or British Muslims,
or Muslims living in the United Kingdom to become Christians.
One of the arguments they use.
The same way, it is responsibility of us in the United States to counter that in the United States, and I hope so سبحانه وتعالى to assist us all in that task.
اسلام علیکم وعلیکم سلام
Concerning Dawah to the Kafir(کافر), since most translations of Qur'an have in Arabic as well as in English, is it okay to give a Kafir(کافر) the Qur'an containing the Arabic?
It is merely Fiqh(فقہ) point of view, the majority of scholars say it is permissible, given that the content, the English content, is greater than the Arabic content,
so therefore they consider it like a book of Tafseer(تفسیر) or so forth.
However, though my personal feeling is that whenever we can avoid that
it should be real that Christians or at least I know, in fact, the Westerners in America do strange things, like, for instance, sit on the toilet and read,
and they also sometimes will not respect our book.
And there have been incidents where we know people become Muslim because they have found, for instance, Qurans in the trash cans so forth.
And they just would take it home, and then, you know, they would read, and that was a cause for them to become Muslims.
So I always suggest that the people need to produce Qur'ans in a merely English text, without the Arabic there,
in order that this can be distributed and then if a Kafir(کافر) does, throws it away or defiles it, it causes no sin engaged to us,
although I mean from just the mere point most of scholars have permitted the distribution of these Qur'an to the non Muslims.
Okay, these are going to be the last two.
Would it be possible to get a copy of the Christian statistics?
Yes, I'll leave a copy or, like one of the brothers here to photocopy, and then whoever can take it from Muntadhar
Missionaries are going to schools and telling Muslim children, we will give you good houses and monies.
Can you leave your families; The school is here.
So parents should be aware of this. And I think that whoever is aware of this information should perhaps give a lecture in the conference or in the Masjid to make people aware.
I've also been asked to announce this announcement for the sake of the brothers and sisters here
that Muntadah Islamic Second Annual Conference, Thoughts on Dawah(دعوۃ) Sixth and 7th of April, 1996
which I guess is next weekend.
We have “Sheikh Abu Ameenah Bilal Phillips” and “Sheikh Hashim Refai” and accommodation, meals are available.
Fees 15 pounds only meals and accommodation required.
Please bring your sleeping bag. Brothers and Sisters are welcome
free crocheting, I have no idea what means the word crochet for children, and registration starts at 10 am Saturday, 6th of April,
and you can contact me later for details.
جزاک اللہ خیرا
As I thank the brothers and sisters for patiently listening to us and though trouble with the sound of the audio.
سُبْحَانَکَ اللّٰھُمَّ وَبِحَمْدِکَ اَشْھَدُ اَنْ لَّآ اِلٰہَ اِلَّآ اَنْتَ اَسْتَغْفِرُکَ وَاَتُوْبُ اِلَیْکَ
والسلام علیکم ورحمۃ اللہ وبرکاتہ